Can you help me check the PowerPoint
I made for the presentation?
So you are using visual aids in your presentation?
That’s good
Do you know people absorb 80 percent
of the information they learn through seeing?
That’s why visual aids are
so effective in presentations
I’ve included graphs and charts in my slides
Charts, such as pie charts and bar charts
show the percentage and the breakdown of the data
What other visual aids can I use?
There are tables and figures
which we find more often on printed materials
We can also use diagrams, such as flow charts
to explain a process or procedure
The use of video and images can also
successfully communicate ideas
and attract people’s attention, right?
After all, “a picture is worth a thousand words.”
How many slides do you plan to use in your PowerPoint?
Not too many, just about 50.
That’s a lot
You should keep the number of slides to a minimum
You don’t need to put everything you say on them
Ok, I will cut down the number of slides
for my presentation.
I also need to enlarge the font size
and change the style
I think I included too many words
and images on a single slide
You should limit the amount of material on each slide
The visual aid should be visible
to the entire audience
After finishing all the slides
I will double check the spelling
and grammar for mistakes
Now that you have all the slides ready
it’s crucial to run through them
before the actual presentation
Yes. That’s called a “technical rehearsal,” right?
Right. Set up the audio and video equipment
and test them
Get everything ready before the presentation
Also, during the presentation
you can check with the audience by asking
“Can everyone hear clearly?”
or “Can you see the screen from the back row?”
Should I introduce the visual aid to the audience
when they first see it?
Talk about the visual aid by pointing to the screen
“As you can see from this graph…”
or “This chart gives you a breakdown of…”
Visual aids can really enhance the core message
and help the audience understand the information better
Following the slides can help the presenter
focus on the subject, too.
Let me show you some pictures I’m putting on my slides
Those pictures are great
Now you’re making the best use of your visual aids